CURRICULUM VITAE

Weiguo Huang

Industry: Software development

Address: Timperley, Altrincham, WA15 7GH

Phone: 07529151452, Mon-Fri 10:00 AM-12:00 AM, I will call back quickly if there is no

response. Welcome to contact me via email.

Email: timhung1221@gmail.com

in Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/weiguo-h-7976a4128

Gender: Male **Birth:** Nov. 1969

Ethnic: Chinese **Work permit:** UK Citizen

English level: B1 (Intermediate)

Personal statement

I am an excellent team worker and am able to take instructions from all levels and build up good working relationships with all colleagues. I am flexible, reliable and possess excellent time keeping skills. I am an enthusiastic, self-motivated, reliable, responsible and hard-working person. I have a passion for software development work. I am currently seeking an opportunity to join a company that can help me enhance my software development skills, deepen my knowledge, and realize my potential.

I like to develop programs using C#. I can start immediately if develop desktop application using C#, and I need short-term training if develop Web application. I am open to exploring various opportunities that allow me to apply the knowledge I have gained in software development. Through my long-term work in software development, I have formed my own development experience in some areas of software development and mastered a set of laws of software development work. I really like to use C#, because this language is a compiled language, which can avoid many runtime errors, and C# is similar to Java or C++, the code structure is very scientific and reasonable. Based on the skills I currently have, I think I can use C# to develop all software programs. Of course, in other areas, such as AI, it is more reasonable to use Python. Because AI technology has already accumulated an irreversible amount of program code using Python. I have already learned Python, and except for the fact that the IDE is not very friendly, there is no problem with other aspects. However, I do not oppose the use of other programming languages. At the OOP level, high-level languages are the same. Solving software functional problems is the primary task, so using other programming languages is no problem for me, and I can master them in a short time.

I expect that I will not only be an employee, but also that I can become a partner of the company in the future through my efforts and contribute my greatest strength to the development of the company. I can start working immediately.

Key Skills

4 years C# experience,

2 years SQL/Oracle experience,

4 years VB5 experience,

1 year VC++ experience,

1 year C experience.

Python/HTML/JavaScript/Web Apps with ASP.NET Certificated

Employment History

Date: Apr. 2022 - Present

Organization: Hyperiondev, freeCodeCamp, codecademy

Job Title: Student

Resp./Skills: Software development skill learning

Python and SQLite

- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures
- Scientific Computing with Python
- Responsive Web Design
- Front End Development Libraries
- React Basic
- Build Web Apps with ASP.NET Skill Path

Date: Jan. 2021 – Apr. 2022 Organization: AS UK logistic Ltd. (UK)

Job Title: Supervisor Resp./Skills: Warehouse work

Date: Nov. 2018 – Dec. 2020
Organization: AS UK logistic Ltd. (UK)
Job Title: Worker (Part time)
Resp./Skills: Warehouse work

Date: Sep. 2017 – Oct. 2018
Organization: Tom JL Ltd. (UK)
Job Title: Inventory supervisor
Resp./Skills: Inventory management

Date: Jun. 2016 – Aug. 2017
Organization: Warrantec Company (UK)
Job Title: Inventory supervisor
Resp./Skills: Inventory management

Date: Sep. 2015 – May. 2016

Organization: Manchester adult learning center

Job Title: Student

Resp./Skills: ESOL (English for Speakers of Other Languages) learning, Level Entry 3

Date: Jul. 2013 – Mar. 2015

Organization: Taylor research Ltd. (UK)

Job Title: SEO maintenance

Resp./Skills: Search engines optimization, Wordpress website maintenance

Date: Sep. 2009 – Feb. 2013
Organization: Shulan UK Ltd. (UK)
Job Title: Warehouse supervisor
Resp./Skills: Inventory management

Date: Nov 2006 – Oct 2008

Organization: Jerit Tech. Ltd. (Chengdu city, China)

Job Title: Team leader/Software developer

Resp./Skills:

- Software development in C# and VB5(ocx control)
- · Windows desktop software design/test/release
- OOP
- Web applications (ASP.NET) development
- Systems analysis/design(Software & Database)/test/release
- Software development life cycle
- Source version control (Microsoft Visual SourceSafe)
- Database maintenance (MS SQL 2000/2005 & Oracle 9i)
- Generation PDF
- Develop tools: VB6, C# 2005, SQL Server 2000/2005, Oracle 9i.

Date: Jul 2005 – Oct 2006

Organization: BaiBei Science Tech. Ltd(Chengdu, China)

Job Title: Team leader/Software development

Resp./Skills:

- Software development in C#/VB.NET
- Systems analysis
- Web applications (ASP.NET)
- OCR tech application
- Data upload
- Scan Driver
- Develop tools: C++, VB.NET/C# 2003/2005, SQL Server 2000.

Date: Mar. 2005 – Jun. 2005

Organization: ChengDu Summit Softwear Co Ltd. (China)

Job Title: Software Engineer/Development Team Leader

Resp./Skills:

- Development management
- Requirements capture
- Systems analysis
- Systems design (Software)
- Software test
- Recruitment
- Develop tools: VB.NET/C#Net 2005/VC 6, SQL Server 2000, Pocket PC.

Date: Mar. 1998 – Jun. 2003

Organization: HuaZhenLian Industry Company (China)

Job Title: Software Engineer/Development Team Leader

Resp./Skills:

• Development management

Requirements capture

• Systems analysis/design/test

- Windows desktop software design
- Develop tools: VC6/VB4/VB6 SQL Server 2000, Oracle 7.

Date: Jul. 1997 – Feb. 1998

Organization: ChuangLiHeng communication Tec. Ltd. (China)

Job Title: Software Engineer

Resp./Skills:

• Software Programming for DLL.

Software Testing

Develop tools: VC4, SQL server 7.

Date: Mar. 1995 – Jun. 1997 Organization: Group Sense (HK)

Job Title: Assistant Software Engineer

Resp./Skills:

• Embed programming for electronic dictionary

• Develop tools: Borland C/C++ 3.0

Education

Sep. 1990 – Jul. 1993 – Three years college diploma Economic Management Sichuan University, China

Sep. 1984 – Jul. 1987 – Technical school Computer Science Application Computer Profession School, China

Certificate

May. 2022 - Dec. 2023 Org: Codecademy

Certification type: Single Subject Certification

Items:

Learn React,

Build Web Apps with ASP.NET Skill Path

Apr. 2022 - Dec. 2023 Org: freeCodeCamp

Certification type: Single Subject Certification

Items:

Scientific Computing with Python

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

Responsive Web Design

Front End Development Libraries

Nov. 2022 – Apr. 2023

Org: HyperionDev & The University of Manchester Certification type: Software Engineering Certificated

Items:

Python science application

Sep. 2015 - May. 2016

Org: Manchester Adult Learning Centre
Certification type: Single Subject Certification

Items: ESOL (English for Speakers of Other Languages)

ESOL Entry 3 Writing & Reading

ESOL Entry 2 Listening

Mar. 2004 - Mar. 2005

Org: NIIT (National Institute Of Information Technology), China

Certification type: Software Engineering Certificated

Items:

- HTML
- CSS
- JAVA
- J2EE
- C#
- SQL

Nov. 2000 – Apr. 2001

Org: SCO, China

Certification type: Software Engineering Certificated

Items:

UNIX

Hobbies & Interests

Swimming, Hiking, Reading, Computer skill, Al skill

References

- Certificate
- Windows Desktop App Demo
- Python App Demo
- HTML Demo
- ❖ JavaScript Demo

Certificated:

















